Luiz Felipe Vecchietti

Ifelipesv@gmail.com · +82-10-4964-0418 https://Ifelipesv.github.io/

42 Eoeun-ro 51beon-gil 203, Eoeun-dong, Yuseong-gu, Daejeon, South Korea, 34139 Last Updated: July, 2022

RESEARCH INTERESTS

I am an electronics and computer engineer interested in artificial intelligence, applied deep learning, reinforcement learning, and bioinformatics. I am currently working towards applying AI-based methods for Protein and Antibody Design applied to drug discovery. I am also interested in improving exploration and credit assignment in single-agent and multi-agent reinforcement learning. My main research interests are deep learning applications in robotics, data science, natural language processing and bioinformatics. I have previous research experiences in speech synthesis, natural language processing (using recurrent neural networks and transformers), and robotic applications using continuous control.

Positions

Data Science Group, Institute for Basic Science

Daejeon, South Korea, Oct. 2021 - Present

Senior Researcher.

Mechanical Engineering Research Institute, KAIST

Daejeon, South Korea, Mar. 2021 - Sep. 2021

Postdoctoral Researcher.

EDUCATION

Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST)

Daejeon, South Korea, Aug. 2017 - Feb. 2021

P.h.D. in Green Transportation. Advisor: Dongsoo Har.

Thesis topic: Performance Enhancement in Multigoal Reinforcement Learning using Hindsight Experience Replay.

COPPE - Federal University of Rio de Janeiro (UFRJ)

Rio de Janeiro, Brazil, Mar. 2015 - Apr. 2017

M.S. in Electrical Engineering. Advisor: Fernando Gil Vianna Resende Junior.

Thesis topic: Comparison between rule-based and data-driven Natural Language Processing algorithms for Brazilian Portuguese Speech Synthesis.

Federal University of Rio de Janeiro (UFRJ)

Rio de Janeiro, Brazil, Feb. 2009 - Dec. 2014

B.S. in Electronics and Computer Engineering.

Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST)

Daejeon, South Korea, Feb. 2013 - Feb. 2014

Exchange Student in Electrical Engineering (Science without Borders Program).

SELECTED PAPERS

- [1] M. Seo, L. F. Vecchietti, S. Lee and D. Har, "Rewards Prediction-Based Credit Assignment for Reinforcement Learning With Sparse Binary Rewards," in IEEE Access, vol. 7, pp. 118776-118791, 2019, doi: 10.1109/AC-CESS.2019.2936863.
- [2] L. F. Vecchietti, M. Seo and D. Har, "Sampling Rate Decay in Hindsight Experience Replay for Robot Control," in IEEE Transactions on Cybernetics, 2020, doi: 10.1109/TCYB.2020.2990722.
- [3] L. F. Vecchietti, T. Kim, K. Choi, J. Hong and D. Har, "Batch Prioritization in Multigoal Reinforcement Learning," in IEEE Access, vol. 8, pp. 137449-137461, 2020, doi: 10.1109/ACCESS.2020.3012204.
- [4] S. Lee, L. F. Vecchietti, H. Jin, J. Hong and D. Har, "Power Management by LSTM Network for Nanogrids," in IEEE Access, vol. 8, pp. 24081-24097, 2020, doi: 10.1109/ACCESS.2020.2969460.

- [5] S. Lee, H. Jin, L. F. Vecchietti, J. Hong and D. Har, "Short-Term Predictive Power Management of PV-Powered Nanogrids," in IEEE Access, vol. 8, pp. 147839-147857, 2020, doi: 10.1109/ACCESS.2020.3015243.
- [6] T. Kim, L. F. Vecchietti, K. Choi, S. Lee and D. Har, "Machine Learning for Advanced Wireless Sensor Networks: A Review," in IEEE Sensors Journal, vol. 21, no. 11, pp. 12379-12397, 1 June1, 2021, doi: 10.1109/JSEN.2020.3035846.
- [7] S. Lee, H. Jin, L. F. Vecchietti, J. Hong, K. Park and D. Har, "Power Management of Nanogrid Cluster with P2P Electricity Trading Based on Future Trends of Load Demand and PV Power Production", 2020, arXiv preprint arXiv:2009.00863
- [8] S. Kim, I. Kim, L. F. Vecchietti and D. Har, "Pose Estimation Utilizing a Gated Recurrent Unit Network for Visual Localization", in Applied Sciences, 10, no. 24: 8876, 2020, https://doi.org/10.3390/app10248876.
- [9] S. Lee, D. Har, L. F. Vecchietti, J. Hong, H.-J. Lim, "Optimal Link Scheduling Based on Attributes of Nodes in 6TiSCH Wireless Networks", in The Journal of Korean Institute of Information Technology, vol. 18, no. 1, pp.77-92, 2020, https://doi.org/10.14801/jkiit.2020.18.1.77.
- [10] C. Hong, I. Jeong, **L. F. Vecchietti**, D. Har and J. -H. Kim, "**Al World Cup: Robot Soccer-Based Competitions**," in IEEE Transactions on Games, 2021, doi: 10.1109/TG.2021.3065410.
- [11] T. Kim, **L. F. Vecchietti**, K. Choi, S. Sariel and D. Har, "**Two-stage training algorithm for AI robot soccer**", in Peer] Computer Science, 7:e718, 2021, https://doi.org/10.7717/peerj-cs.718.
- [12] S. Lee, H. Jin, L. F. Vecchietti, J. Hong, K-B. Park, PN. Son and D. Har, "Cooperative decentralized peer-to-peer electricity trading of nanogrid clusters based on predictions of load demand and PV power generation using a gated recurrent unit model", in IET Renewable Power Generation, vol. 15, pp. 3505-3523, 2021, https://doi.org/10.1049/rpg2.12195.
- [13] M. Lee, A. Rzayev, H. Jung, **L. F. Vecchietti**, M. Cha, H. Kim, "**Structure-based representation for protein functionality prediction using machine learning**", in Proceedings of the Korea Computer Congress (KCC), 2022.

WORK EXPERIENCES

Hyundai Motor Company, Namyang Research and Development Center *Namyang, South Korea, Jul.* 2013 Intern. Advisor: Dong-pil Yoon.

Honors and Awards

Science without Borders Program

Feb. 2013 - Feb. 2014

Brazilian government 1 year scholarship for undergraduate students with outstanding academic achievements.

ACADEMIC SERVICES

Reviewer

IEEE Transactions on Cybernetics

IEEE Sensors

IEEE Transactions on Games

ICML LatinX Workshop 2021

AAAI ICWSM 2022 2022

INVITED PRESENTATIONS

School of AI Convergence - Chonnam National University

Nov. 2021

Invited to present the work titled "Identifying the key actions that lead an agent to accomplish a task in model-based deep reinforcement learning."

Invited to present the work titled "Performance enhancement in multigoal model-based deep reinforcement learning."

Institute for Basic Science (IBS)

Apr. 2021

Invited to present the work titled "Identifying the key actions that lead an agent to accomplish a task in model-based deep reinforcement learning."